dhl-usa.com 2019-12-26

# Local Privacy Notice | DHL | United States of America

##  Categories 

We have provided details of all cookies used on this websites in the table below.  

All cookies in this table have been categorized according to 4 numbered groups. Please note that cookies can belong to more than one category.  

**The categories are as follows:**

¹ Strictly Necessary: These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided. As already stated above, this is based on Art. 6 (1) f) GDPR.

² Performance: These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works.

³ Functionality: These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. For example, these cookies can be used to remember and store the last tracking number that you entered when using a tracking application. Information these cookies collect may be anonymized and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

4 Targeting or Advertising: These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as helping measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission.  

##  List of Cookies 

**Salesforce Marketing Cloud Tracking Cookie ² | Salesforce**

The cookie collects information in an anonymous form unless you contact DHL using certain online contact forms in the Logistics content area. At this point, we link the information stored in the cookie to your email address.

Information gathered includes page views, length of time on a page and the browser you used to view the content. This information helps DHL to measure the performance of email campaigns.

If the cookie remains anonymous, it expires after 30 days. If linked to an email address, it expires 2 years (730 days) after contacts last identified themselves. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve the user experience.   

More Info about Privacy at [Salesforceundefined](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/full_privacy.jsp)

**Campaign Name Cookie ² | campaignName**  

This cookie is created when you arrive at a DHL web page from a DHL promotional banner or from a link contained in a campaign / promotional email. 

The cookie stores a campaign ID, which uniquely identifies the campaign source. 

If you contact DHL using one of our online contact or registration forms within 24 hours of arriving at one of our websites, the campaign ID is attached with the email sent to DHL Sales or Customer Service.

This information is solely used to assess how successful our campaigns are and monitor if customers have contacted us as a result of a campaign. 

The cookie stores no personal customer data at all, only the campaign's ID.

The cookie expires after 24 hours only.

**Search Parameter Cookie ³ | searchParams   **  

This cookie is used to store search phrases and words that you have typed into our Search boxes. 

The Search boxes can be found at the top right of each of our web pages. 

In this way, we remember your search terms and pre-populate the search box with previous suggestions when you reuse the search boxes.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie permanently stores search terms until such a time that you actively decide to clear your browser cache and cookies.

**Shipper Reference Details Cookie ³ | shipRefDetails**  

This cookie is used to store all previously tracked shipper reference values that you enter when using our DHL Express Shipper's Reference tracking application.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie permanently stores all shipper references until such a time that you actively decide to clear your browser cache and cookies.

Take a look at one of our DHL Express Shipper's Reference tracking applications.   

**Waybill Cookie ³ | AWB  **  

This cookie is used to store the last tracking number value that you entered when using one of our main online tracking applications.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie only stores the previous tracking number value until such a time that you enter a new number in the same tracking application.

Take a look at one of our main online tracking applicationsundefined.

**Waybill Brand Cookie ³ | BRAND**  

This cookie is used to store the last shipment type that you selected from the dropdown options that are offered in our main online tracking applications.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie only stores the previous shipment type dropdown option selected until such a time that you return and select another option in the same tracking application.

Take a look at one of our main online tracking applications.  

**Fast Track Cookie ³ | No fixed name**  

This cookie is used to store both the last tracking number value entered and the shipment type selected from the dropdown when using our smaller Fast Track online tracking applications.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie only stores the previous tracking number value and previous shipment type dropdown option selected until such a time that you return and select new options in the same Fast Track tracking application.

You can find one of our DHL Express Fast Track tracking applications here.  

**Tab System Cookie ³ | No fixed name**  

This cookie is used to store the last tab that you selected on a page using a multi-view tab system.

This cookie has been created to improve website functionality and make using DHL websites easier for our customers.

This cookie only remembers the previous tab selected until you return and select another tab on the same tabbed page.

**Webtrends Analytics ² | WT_FPC**  

This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

The cookie is only used for identification and does not hold visitor personal data, only an identifier. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience.

More Info about Privacy at [Webtrendsundefined](https://www.webtrends.com/terms-policies/privacy/privacy-statement/).  

**Webtrends Analytics ² | ACOOKIE**

This cookie is used to collect information about how visitors use our sites and is specifically used to monitor visitors across DHL domains.  

For example, if a visitor arrives at our corporate site (domain is [www.logistics.dhlundefined](https://www.logistics.dhl/global-en/home.html)) and then selects to visit a DHL country website with its own local domain (e.g. for Germany, local domain is [www.dhl.deundefined](https://www.dhl.de/en.html)).  

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  

The cookie is only used for identification and does not hold visitor personal data, only an identifier. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience.  

More Info about Privacy at [Webtrendsundefined](https://www.webtrends.com/terms-policies/privacy/privacy-statement/)

**Google Analytics ² | _utma, _utmb; utmz**  

A small number of countries may use Google Analytics cookies on a small scale for specific local purposes. These cookies use your IP address as recognition; however do not identify you as an individual. In other words, information is collected in a pseudonymous form. The cookies collect information about how visitors use our local sites and use the information to compile reports and to help us improve local sites.

More Info about Privacy at [Googleundefined](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

**Eloqua Tracking Cookie ² | ELOQUA**  

The content of this persistent tracking cookie is limited to an identification number and is generally used in exactly the same way as all of our other persistent cookies. However, if you contact DHL using certain online contact forms in the Logistics content area, your email address is added to the cookie to create an individual profile of your online activities. These same contact forms also provide you with an option to sign up for email marketing updates. By giving your permission, this also allows us to provide you with personalized content, offers or promotions that may interest you. Should you choose not to sign up for email marketing updates, you will not be contacted in the future and your email address will only be used confidentially by DHL internally to understand your individual online activities. This means that we can still continue to deliver new and improved website content to suit your specific needs.

More Info about Privacy at [Eloquaundefined](https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/products/marketing-automation/index.html)  

**LiveBall Tracking Cookies ² | LiveBall, mkto_trk, ki_r, ki_t, ki_u**  

These cookies collect information using anonymous identification numbers.

LiveBall uses IP address to provide non-intrusive geographical location data, however it is not saved in or linked with the cookie. This helps us to track web browsing behavior in order to understand and improve the user experience and the services that we offer. However, it cannot be mapped back to your personal data. 

These cookies are set when you contact DHL using certain online forms on our websites – for example, when you open a DHL Express account with us. 

The cookies are used confidentially only by DHL internally and expire after 365 days.

More info about [Privacy](https://www2.ioninteractive.com/privacy-policy)

**dotdigital Tracking Cookie ² | tracked_session**  

This cookie is created when you arrive at specific web pages from a link contained in a campaign or promotional email. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site and provide you with better, targeted content.

The cookie collects information in an anonymous form unless you contact DHL using certain online contact forms in the Logistics content area. At this point, we link the information stored in the cookie to your email address to create an individual profile of your online activities. These same contact forms also provide you with an option to sign up for email marketing updates. By giving your permission, this also allows us to provide you with personalized content, offers or promotions that may interest you.

Information gathered includes page views, length of time on a page and the browser you used to view the content. This information helps DHL to measure the performance of email campaigns.

If the cookie remains anonymous, it expires after 30 days. If linked to an email address, it expires 1 year (365 days) after contacts last identified themselves. It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve the user experience.

Should you choose not to sign up for email marketing updates, you will not be contacted in the future and your email address will only be used confidentially by DHL internally to understand your individual online activities. This means that we can still continue to deliver new and improved website content to suit your specific needs.    

More info about privacy at [dotdigital](https://support.dotdigital.com/hc/en-gb/articles/115001414144-What-type-of-cookies-do-you-create-on-the-devices-of-recipients-and-visitors-)

**MediaMind Cookies ² | U2, ActivityInfo, TargetingInfo, Eyeblaster, A3, B4, and C4.**  

MediaMind cookies are created when you arrive at specific DHL campaign web pages from a DHL promotional banner, from a link contained in a campaign / promotional email, or when you have used a campaign link provided as part of an offline media advertisement. MediaMind cookies track when and where you were exposed to DHL ads online, how you engaged with those ads, and when you visited the DHL site after being exposed to those ads.

The information is used to help DHL measure the performance of advertising campaigns. The information is provided as aggregated reports, so no individual user information will be viewed. It does not monitor any other browsing behavior and is used confidentially only by DHL internally.

These persistent tracking cookies collect your IP address and use it to provide geographical location data to help DHL monitor and manage advertising campaigns. The cookies are completely encrypted and do not collect any other personally-identifiable data, so the IP address cannot be linked to personal data and is not shared with third parties. The IP address is stored securely and only used confidentially by DHL internally to provide aggregated reports. The cookies expire after 30 days.  

More Info about Privacy at [MediaMind](https://www.sizmek.com/privacy-policy/optedin/)

**Flash Cookies ¹ | LSO**  

Flash Cookies allow you to view Flash Player content and are independent of DHL.

Flash Player default settings do not seek user's permission to store cookies on local hard disk.

If you wish, you can disable flash cookies (also referred to as 'local shared objects').

More info about how to manage or disable [Flash Cookies](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html)  

Full info on [Flash Player functionality and related Privacy settings](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/help01.html)

**You Tube Cookies ² | use_hitbox VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE   **  

We embed videos using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. Some of these videos are from our official YouTube channel. 

This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.

To find out more, please visit [YouTube's embedding videos information page](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/171780?hl=en-GB)

**Decibel Insight cookies ² | da_sid, da_lid**  

In order to provide better content and service, this site uses the Decibel Insight web analytics service. This site does not use Decibel Insight to collect any information that may be personally identifiable to you. Decibel Insight may record mouse actions and scrolling movement, as well as basic interactions with website forms. Decibel Insight does not track your browsing habits across other third-party websites. For more information about the data practices of Decibel Insight, please visit their privacy policy - [https://www.decibelinsight.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.decibelinsight.com/privacy-policy/)

You can opt out of Decibel Insight tracking by visiting [www.decibelinsight.com/optout](https://www.decibelinsight.com/optout)

**Usabilla Cookies | usbl.c.ID**  

The following data is stored for Usabilla campaigns:

  * Whether or not the campaign has already been run, if so, the campaign will not be shown again.
  * If the campaign has a "N% chance" trigger it stores whether or not the campaign should be shown at all.
  * If the campaign should be triggered after the visitor has visited a certain amount of pages, the number of pages visited since the campaign was started are stored.

This data is stored in HTML5 Local Storage, with one entry per campaign. The key of this field is "usbl.c.ID" where ID is a unique id for the campaign.

Furthermore, if the "new or returning visitor"-trigger is enabled in any campaign the following two pieces of data will be stored:

  1.  The field "usbl.v" in Local Storage
  2.  A session cookie named "usbls"

These two pieces of data are needed to determine if a user is new or returning. If you want to know more about Usabilla's cookie policy, please check: [https://usabilla.com/cookie-policyundefined](https://usabilla.com/cookie-policy)

**Adobe Marketing Cloud Cookies ²**  

These cookies are used to collect information in an anonymous form about how visitors use the website. The information is used to improve the site and provide users with content that is more appropriate to them.

AMCV_###@AdobeOrg  
This cookie is used to identify a unique visitor. This is a permanent cookie which expires after 2 years.

mbox  
This cookie is used for onsite personalization and determines which dynamic content is shown to a user. The cookie remains on the visitor's browser two weeks from his or her last login.

s_cc  
This cookie determines whether cookies are enabled in the browser. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

s_vi  
This cookie is used to identify unique visitor time/date stamp. This is a permanent cookie which expires after 5 years.  

s_fid  
This cookie is a 'fallback' visitor identifier where the s_vi cookie normally used for this purpose is blocked. It contains a randomly generated, unique id.  

s_sq  
This cookie records what links the user has clicked. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

s_nr  
This cookie stores the information of the date of visit and if a visitor is new or returning. This is a permanent cookie which expires after 2 years.  

s_ppn  
This cookie records the name of the previously viewed page on the site. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

s_ppv  
This cookie records if a user has previously viewed a page and is captured on the following page. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

s_ppvl  
This cookie records the name of the latest viewed page on the site. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

_sdsat_landing_page  
This cookie determines which site was first visited during a visit session. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

_sdsat_lt_pages_viewed  
This cookie determines how many pages where viewed during a visit session. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

_sdsat_session_count  
This cookie determines how often a visitor has visited the site. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.  

_sdsat_traffic_source  
This cookie determines from which page a visitor has been referred to the site. This cookie is a session cookie and will expire when the browser is closed.

More Info about Privacy at [Adobeundefined](https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/whitepapers/cookies/cookies_analytics.html)  

**Google Adwords Cookies 4 | Various: see [Types of cookies used by Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types)**

When you click on an ad delivered by Google, a conversion tracking cookie is placed on your browser. These cookies expire after 30 days, do not contain any personal data and therefore cannot be used to identify you personally. If you visit certain pages on our website and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google can tell that you clicked on the ad and were directed to that page. Each Google AdWords customer has a different cookie, so it is not possible to track cookies via websites of other AdWords customers. The information collected by means of the conversion cookie is used to compile conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers can see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were directed to a page containing a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive information that enables them to identify users personally.

More info about Google Adwords in Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)  
To opt out of being tracked by Google Adwords across all websites, visit: [Google Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

**DoubleClick Cookies 4 | Various: see [Types of cookies used by Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types)**

We use the online advertising program DoubleClick and the conversion tracking function of DoubleClick. DoubleClick conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google.  
When you click on a Google or Bing advertisement, a cookie is placed on your browser. This enables both DoubleClick and DHL to recognize that someone has been redirected to the website from a Google or Bing ad and has made it to a predetermined target page (conversion page).

The cookies enable us to count the number of times a user visits a web page after clicking on one of our ads and to track the number of sales made. These cookies do not collect any personally-identifiable data.

More info about DoubleClick in Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)  
If you do not want to take part in the tracking process outlined here, you can decline the placement of the cookie necessary for this to take place over your browser settings. You can also opt out of DoubleClick's use of cookies by visiting [Google Ad Settings.](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

**Google Remarketing and Similar Audience Technology 4 | Various: see [Types of cookies used by Google](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types)**

Our websites use retargeting and similar audience technology provided by Google. This technology enables us to target visitors of our website with remarketing ads who already have shown interest in our products. The ads are displayed by using a cookie-based analysis of the previous usage data. Personal data will not be stored. In the case of retargeting technology, a cookie will be stored on your browser in order to collect anonymized date about your interests and adapt ads specifically according to the stored information. Later, if you perform Google searches or see advertisements from the Google network on other websites, we have the possibility of presenting you targeted ads of our products there (known as remarketing). If you have a Google account, Google can link this data with your Google account.  
Similar audience targeting allows DHL to show ads to people who share characteristics with people on the existing remarketing lists.

More info, including how remarketing works in Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)  
You can deactivate remarketing ads from Google by visiting [Google Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

**Microsoft Bing Cookies 4 | Various: see Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies in the [Microsoft Privacy Statement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en/privacystatement)**

Our websites use the conversion tracking of Bing Ads. When you click on a Bing advertisement, a cookie is placed on your browser. This enables both Bing and DHL to recognize that someone has been redirected to the website from a Bing ad and has made it to a predetermined target page (conversion page).

More info about Microsoft Bing in Microsoft’s [Privacy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en/privacystatement) Statement.  
If you do not want to take part in the tracking process outlined here, you can decline the placement of the cookie necessary for this to take place over your browser settings. The deactivation can be carried out using the [Microsoft Opt Out](http://choice.microsoft.com/en/opt-out).

**Get a Quote 4 | _gaq_data**

This cookie is used for reidentifying and restoring recent quote information for quote data requested on logistics.dhl. This cookie stores required fields in order to perform a quote request. These are country, city and zip data for the origin and destination. Information regarding the parcel attributes and delivery date. The cookie does not store any personal information. The cookie will be stored for two years.

##  Additional Information 

**Sharing Tools: Third Party Cookies**

DHL now uses embedded 'share' buttons on its websites. These make it easy for visitors to bookmark and share content through their favorite social networks. When you click on one of these buttons, a cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. DHL does not control the use of these cookies and you should therefore check the relevant third party's website for more information. The 'share buttons' are provided by AddThis. For more information about their data collection practices, please take a look at the [AddThis Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/terms-of-service).

**Third Party Cookies in embedded content**  

Please note that on some pages of our websites you may notice that cookies have been set that are not related to DHL. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Vimeo, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browser. DHL does not control the use of these cookies and cannot access them due to the way that cookies work, as cookies can only be accessed by the party who originally set them. You should check the third party websites for more information about these cookies.

**Web Beacons**  

In order to keep DHL's online content relevant, easy to use and up-to-date, we use web analytics services such as Adobe Analytics and Webtrends (see Webtrends entry in DHL Table of Cookies above for more information.) to help us understand how people use our websites. These services use data collection technologies such as web beacons. Web beacons are small electronic images that deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage and website effectiveness. In turn, this lets us know what content is of interest to our visitors and helps us provide tailored information on our websites. These web beacons are anonymous and do not contain or collect any information that identifies you. The information is anonymous and only used for statistical purposes. These web analytics data and cookies cannot be used to identify you as a natural person as they never contain personal information such as your name or email address.
